Finding Aid for Ermine Cowles Case papers, 1805-1956
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Professional Files (1907-1952)
  - Speeches and Talks 1909-1947
    - Azazels Club 1941, 1943 (Box 3)
    - Club 1935-1947 (Box 3)
    - Junior Research Club undated (Box 3)
    - Memorial of Professor Hugo Thieme 1940 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Academic Society 1912, 1938 (Box 3)
    - Paleontology Society 1929 (Box 3)
    - Pharmacists 1925 (Box 3)
    - Phi Lambda Upsilon undated (Box 3)
    - Phi Sigma, pre-1919-1946 (Box 3)
    - Research Club 1909-1940 (Box 3)
    - Rotary Club 1920 (Box 3)
    - Russell Lecture 1934 (Box 3)
    - Sigma Gamma Epsilon circa 1927-1929, undated (Box 3)
    - Sigma Xi 1921, 1942 (Box 3)
    - University Club circa 1912 (Box 3)
    - University Lecture 1934 (Box 3)
    - Unknown Events circa 1911-1947 (Box 3)
    - Unknown and Undated Events (Box 3)
- Personal Files (1805-1953)
  The Personal Files are arranged into five subseries: biographical records, correspondence, journals and notebooks, planners, and ration books. The biographical records contain an autobiography of E.C. Case in addition to various biographical materials. The correspondences contain letters from his family, and documentation pertaining to his father and the passing of his wife. They also contain special letters from friends, and letters from Alexander Winchell to A. O. Carrier Esq. regarding specimen collection, geological surveys, and the geographical distribution of animals. The journals and notebooks consist of several volumes of travel narratives, research, notes, and sketches. The planners and point ration books are mostly from the 1940s.
  - Biographical and Autobiographical
    - Autobiography, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Biographical Materials (Box 3)
  - Correspondence 1805-1953
    - Family
      - Case, Francis (son) 1943-1952 (Box 3)
      - Case, George B. (cousin) 1931-1939 (Box 3)
      - Case Grandchildren circa 1952 (Box 3)
        (cards and drawings)
      - Case, Johnston Lykins (brother) 1915-1951 (Box 3)
        (includes photographs of family)
      - Case, Rosemary (daughter-in-law) 1930-1953 (Box 3)
        (includes photographs of granddaughters)
      - Case, Theodore J. (son) 1923-1951 (Box 3)
      - Case, Theodore S. (father)
        - Miscellaneous 1805, 1862, 1890s (Box 3)
        - Pottawatomie Massacre (regarding) 1883 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous 1920-1953 (Box 3)
    - Special Letters
      - American Philosophical Society 1952-1953 (Box 3)
      - Azazels and Pleasant Lakes Clubs 1947-1951 (Box 3)
      - Case, Ermine Cowles (excerpts from letters -- Moscow to Tokyo) 1937 (Box 3)
      - Case, Ermine Cowles (letters to his wife, Mary-Margaret) 1916 (Box 3)
      - Death and Burial of Mrs. Mary-Margaret Case 1923-1926 (Box 3)
      - Schauffler, Robert McE. 1930-1951 (Box 3)
      - Smithe, Geneva 1936-1953 (Box 3)
      - Snow, Edith Huntington 1952-1953 (Box 3)
      - Winchell, Alexander 1859-1870 (Box 3)
        (include letters to A. O. Carrier Esq. regarding specimen collection, geological surveys, and the geographical distribution of animals,)
  - Journals and Notebooks
    - 1922-1923 (Journal 1) (Box 4)
    - 1922-1923 (Journal 2) (Box 4)
    - 1923 (Box 4)
    - 1924-1925 (Box 4)
    - 1925 (Box 4)
    - 1929-1930 (Box 4)
    - 1930 (Box 4)
    - 1931 (Box 4)
    - 1932-1934 (Box 4)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 4)
    - 1937 The Peregrinations and Cogitations of a Tramp Professor (Box 4)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 4)
    - Undated (Box 4)
  - Planners
    - 1942 (Box 4)
    - 1943 (Box 4)
    - 1944 (Box 4)
    - 1945 (Box 4)
    - 1946 (Box 4)
    - 1947 (Box 4)
    - 1948 (Box 4)
    - 1949 (Box 4)
    - 1950 (Box 4)
  - Calendar of Memory for 1942 (Box 4)
  - Point Ration Books 1940s
    (includes a Point Ration Book wallet and an Office of Price Administration 1 Red Point piece)
    - Book One -- No. 262630 (Box 4)
    - Book Two -- No. 456240 (Box 4)
    - Book Three -- No. 501028 (Box 4)
    - Book Four -- No 134182 (Box 4)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials mostly consist of photographs. One large portion of photographic materials includes photos of E.C. Case, and his friends and colleagues. There are also photos of fossils, Case's travels, and photos from W. H. Buettner. Among the other visual materials are photo negatives, slides, postcards, and wood etchings by Paul C. Miller.
  - Photographs
    - Personal (Box 4)
      (includes photos of E.C. Case and his family friends, and colleagues)
    - Buettner, William H. (Box 4)
      (Photographed Dinosaur Paintings)
    - Fossils and Skeletons (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Travel Photos (Box 4)
  - Photo Negatives (Box 4)
  - Post Cards (Box 4)
  - Slides (Box 4)
  - Wood Etchings by Paul C. Miller (Box 4)
  - Portrait circa 1930s (Box 5)
  - Photo Album circa 1917-1930 (scattered dates): include photos of field trips to Texas and other places, photos of University of Michigan buildings and athletic events, and family activities (Box 5)
  - Loose photos from album (Box 5)